Peganov Nikita

Backend Developer

Backend developer with working experience in highload systems and project management. Specialize in Python with 3 years of production development experience. I am fond of creating IT-startups, generating ideas and learning new technologies. I am in Moscow now and ready to relocate.

EXPERIENCE

Yandex. Moscow

February 2023 — Now

Middle Python Developer in Infrastructure L3 Management

- reduced the service status update time from 7 minutes to 1 minute using database denormalization
- developed a collector of metrics about services and balancers, and was responsible for its stability
- integrated mechanism for providing alerts to users that sends alerts within 30 seconds

Yandex, Moscow

July 2022 - October 2022

Intern Python Developer of a compensation calculation system in HR-Tech

- added processing of uploads to the system reducing user work time by 50%
- implemented uploading of all user data to the cloud to increase system fault tolerance
- solved 23 minor tasks and wrote unit tests for them to improve the system

Yandex, Moscow

July 2021 — November 2021

Intern Python Developer in traffic management team

- reduced by 50% the load on the servers with DB by translating readonly requests to replicas
- added ipv6 processing into balancers' work allowed to use new ip's without extra 900 lines
- created an internal library redirecting the request to the nearest datacenter

PROJECTS

Tinkoff, Moscow

October 2023 — April 2024

Java Developer, Project Manager

Tukach: The system for accepting applications for violations of corporate ethics

- developed a telegram bot for accepting applications that received 90% positive reviews
- assembled a team of 4 programmers and led it, all deadlines were met
- collected the requirements from the customer, came up with several additional ideas

Huawei, Moscow

November 2021 - May 2022

Python Developer, Data Scientist

Research work «Reinforcement learning for resource allocation tasks in the cloud»

- tested the applicability of reinforcement learning in real conditions
- created and trained a neural network processing 4500 requests per hour
- the total number of processed requests was 1.5 million

Startup SmartLearning, Moscow

November 2020 — March 2021

Kotlin Developer, SEO the development of the Android-application for quick learning

- assembled and managed a team of 4 programmers
- developed an Android application downloaded by 183 users
- took the 19th place at the HSE Fest startup competition

EDUCATION

Higher School of Economics, Moscow

September 2020 - July 2024

Bachelor in Computer Science

- Graduated courses with excellence: C++ Programming, Introduction to Applied Analytics, Databases, Calculus, Discrete Mathematics, English for Business Purposes
- Completed courses: Operating Systems, Software Design on Java, Algorithms and Data Structures, Computer System Architecture, Algebra, Software Development Methodologies, Probability Theory
- •Research works in the field of neural networks were rated 9 out of 10 by scientific supervisors

Moscow, Russia

t.me/peganov ns

peganov.nik@gmail.com +7 (985) 696-83-57github.com/NikPeg gitlab.com/peganov.nik

COMPUTER SKILLS

Python (Django, Jupyter, numpy, sympy, sklearn) Java (Sockets, JavaFX,

Multithreading, Derby,

Spring)

C/C++

(Multithreading, STL)

C#

(Requests, Windows forms)

Kotlin (Android) \mathbf{SQL}

(SQLite, PostgreSQL)

TECHNOLOGIES

Git

Linux

gRPC

Docker

Selenium

Telegram API

ChatGPT API

JetBrains IDEs

LANGUAGES

English (B2)

Russian (Native speaker)

ACHIEVEMENTS

Winner of ITMO "Open Olympiad of schoolchildren

in computer science" (2020)

Winner of "United

Mathematical Olympiad of schoolchildren" (2020)

Medalist of Olympiad of schoolchildren "Fiztech"

in mathematics (2020) Medalist of regional stage

in All-Russian Olympiad of schoolchildren of

CS and ICT (2019)

OTHER COURSES

Summer School of Russian **Association of Artificial** Intelligence (2021)

Tinkoff Generation (2019)

Samsung IT-school (2018)